Norman Zolot Papers 1991.0003
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Norman Zolot Papers
1940-1980.
1991.0003
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
42.0 Linear feet
Norman Zolot is a New Haven, Connecticut, born attorney, and has been active in representing labor unions in the state from the 1940s to the present. The papers consist of his legal case files, primarily concerning labor disputes in the state of Connecticut between the years 1947 and 1979. In addition to legal case files, the collection contains printed reference materials related to state and national labor unions and issues pertaining to the period.
Zolot, Norman.
Biography
Norman Zolot was born in New Haven, Connecticut in 1920 and has resided in and around the city his entire life. A student of New Haven's public school system, Mr. Zolot continued his education in the city attending Yale University after high school. After receiving a Bachelor of Science degree in 1941 Zolot earned his Juris Doctorate from Yale in 1947. Upon completion of law school and admittance to the Connecticut Bar, Mr. Zolot served as a prosecuting attorney for the State of Connecticut, serving from 1947 to 1949 in the New Haven courts.
Mr. Zolot has also devoted much of his legal career to representing labor unions in the state. After serving as a state prosecutor Mr. Zolot became the general councel for the Connecticut branch of the American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations (ALF-CIO), and has remained active in that capacity to the present day. From 1971 until 1989 Mr. Zolot also served as the general counsel for Community Health Care Center Plan in New Haven. In additon to his experience working on behalf of labor unions, Mr. Zolot has been a member of numerous legal organizations and associations and has served on a number of state committees, to include the Connecticut Employment Advisory Committee, the Committee to Study Blue Cross/Blue Shield, the Committee to Study Workers Compensation Law - Compliance with National Standards, the Committee to Study Revision of Workers Compensation Act, and the Committee to Study Municipal Employees Labor Relations. In addittion to his public service, Mr. Zolot maintains a private legal practice in Woodbridge, Connecticut.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Provenance and Acquisition
The collection was originally donated by Norman Zolot to the Connecticut State Library in 1979. In 1991 the Historical Manuscripts and Archives Division at the University of Connecticut requested the transfer of Norman Zolot's papers from the State Library to complete its collection of Connecticut AFL-CIO materials. Mr. Zolot consented to the transfer and the materials were moved from the Connecticut State Library into the Historical Manuscripts and Archives Collections in September 1991.
Scope and Content Note
The Norman Zolot Papers consist of legal case files, primarily concerning labor disputes in the state of Connecticut between the years 1947 and 1979. In addition to legal case files, the collection contains printed reference materials related to state and national labor unions and issues during the period. The collection was originally donated to the Connnecticut State Library in 1979, and was transfered to the University of Connecticut in 1991. There are no restrictions regarding the use of this collection. The papers are organized into five series.
Series I is the largest part of the collection and consists of a variety of legal case files. While each case file represents a distinct conflict, the series consists primarily of labor conflicts between members of labor unions and a company. There are some civil and domestic cases included as well. The series includes cases from 1947 to 1979 with the papers arranged chronologically. The case files were assigned numbers by Norman Zolot, with files occurring prior to 1971 receiving a Case File number (CF1, CF2, etc.). Beginning in 1971 Zolot dropped the case file system and replaced it with the year of the case followed by a numerical designation (1971-1, 1972-1, etc.).
Series II consists of materials related to Norman Zolot's work with the New England Teamster's Pension Fund. The materials included are from the years 1975 to 1979.
Series III consists of case files related to Zolot's participation in a major labor dispute between the United Aircraft Corporation and the International Aerospace Machinists, District 91. Covering the years 1968 to 1971 the files include his notes and correspondence, the briefs and exhibits presented in Hartford Superior Court, the court transcript, and the court's decision.
Series IV consists of individual case files related to labor issues, as well as civil and domestic cases, but that were not given a numerical designation by Zolot. The series contains documents from the years 1953 to 1966.
Series V consists solely of printed reading and reference materials related to state and national labor issues, spanning the years 1947 to 1953. Included in this series are printed flyers and brochures, passed legislation, tax and wage information, and disability and compensation materials.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut labor. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Administrative records.; Connecticut—Labor.; Correspondence.; Financial Records.; Lawyers--Connecticut.; Legal Records.; News clippings.; Photographs.; Posters.; Publications.
- Series I: Legal Case files, 1940s, 1950s, 1960s, 1970s, 1980; 41.3 Linear feet
  - Correspondence, legal documents, manuscript, notes, publications, transcripts, 1947-1950; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_01)
    Scope and Content Note
    [Subjects include: Employment Retirement Plan, Chemical Workers Case Files, Worker’s Association, Case Files # 1-59.]
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, manuscripts, notes, transcripts, 1950-1952; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_02)
    [Subjects include: Case Files # 60-91.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, manuscripts, notes, publications, transcripts, 1949-1954; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_03)
    [Subjects include: Case Files # 92-112.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, legal documents, notes, publications, transcripts, 1950-1954; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_04)
    [Subjects include: Case Files # 113-133.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, legal documents, notes, transcripts, 1956-1957; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_05)
    [Subjects include: Case Files # 134-160.]
  - Administrative records, clippings, financial records, legal documents, notes, publications, transcripts, 1945-1963; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_06)
    [Subjects include: Case Files # 162-185.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, manuscripts, notes, publications, transcripts, 1952-1956; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_07)
    [Subjects include: Case Files # 186-191.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, manuscripts, transcripts, 1950-1957; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_08)
    [Subjects include: Case Files # 192-211.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, maps, notes, publications, transcripts, 1957; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_09)
    [Subjects include: Case Files # 212-228.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, manuscripts, notes, publications, transcripts, 1957-1958; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_10)
    [Subjects include: Case Files # 229-263.]
  - Clippings, correspondence, legal documents, manuscripts, notes, transcripts, 1949-1957; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_11)
    [Subjects include: Case Files # 264-292.]
  - Administrative records, legal documents, manuscripts, notes, transcripts, 1958-1960; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_12)
    [Subjects include: Case Files # 292-306.]
  - Administrative records, financial records, legal documents, manuscripts, transcripts, 1958-1959; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_13)
    [Subjects include: Case Files # 309-325.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, manuscripts, notes, publications, transcripts, 1955-1967; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_14)
    [Subjects include: Case Files # 326-356.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, manuscripts, notes, transcripts, 1956-1960; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_15)
    [Subjects include: Case Files # 357-391.]
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, notes, publications, transcripts, 1952-1963; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_16)
    Subjects include: Case files #392-#429: American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees v. Local 203; Bridgeport Brass Workers, brief- test pump work; Byelas v. Siciliano, Arbitration; Farrell v. Markitan; Fuller Brush, F.L.U., Timekeeper Grievance; I.A.M., Vickers, Committee Discharges; I.B.E.W. Local 90, Paul Kelly, U.L.P.; I.B.T. Local 191, Fairfield County News Company, U.L.P.; I.B.T. Local 191, West End Moving & Storage Company; I.B.T. Local 443, Connecticut Refining Company; I.B.T. Local 443, Schiavone, Pettingell; I.B.T. Local 493, Hess, Incorporated, Arbitration; I.B.T. 493, Spicer Fuel, John R. Hamilton; I.B.T. Local 559, Edward Balf Company, Savin Brothers, Arbitration; I.B.T. Local 559, Edward Balf Company, U.S. District Court, Superior Court; I.B.T. Local 559, Milner Trucking Company, N.L.R.B.; I.B.T. Local 671, Perkins Moving & Storage Company; I.B.T. Local 677, Oates Brothers, N.L.R.B. Election; I.B.T. Local 677, Sega Sand & Gravel, Injunction; I.L.G.W.U., Buonocore, Superior Court Injunction; Joint Council #64, Construction Division; Kyer v. I.B.T. Local 191, U.S. District Court, Hartford; Lombardo, Merryman, United Aircraft U.C.; Manning, Maxwell & Moore, Teamsters; Michael Powers; New England Freight Agreement; New London Metal Trades, Council v. General Dynamics Corporation; Norwich Building Trades, J.S. Nasin; Norwich, Connecticut Building and Construction Trades Council; O'Brien Suburban Press v. I.T.U. 529; Photo Engravers, Local 113, M.S. Chambers & Son, Incorporated; Retail Clerks #282, Regal Drug Company; Shindell, Ketaineck, Fleischner, 173-181 Orchard Street, New Haven; Shindell-Kimberly Hotel Purchase; Stanley Chemical Workers, Arbitration; Tidewater Coal Company; Tire Shop, Incorporated; Wood, Wire, & Metal Lathers International Union.
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, ephemera, financial records, fliers, legal documents, notes, 1960-1974, 1976-1978; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_17)
    Subjects include: Case files #1971.1-#1974.12: A.C.P. Electrical; A.I.W. Local 753; Allen v. Amendola; American Federation of Labor (AFL); Brass Rail, Local 536; Church of Ascension; Connecticut Company, A.T.U. Local 281; Firefighters, Heart Cases; Hartford Carpenters; Holland Dry; I.B.T. Local 536, Election Complaints; I.B.T. Local 671, Miscellaneous; I.B.T. Local 1150; Laborers Ironworkers Teamsters Engineers (L.I.T.E.); Laskas Motors, 677; Local 455 v. Leonard Concrete; Metz v. Metz; Oil Atomic v. Vincent Murray; Roma Construction Company; Sheet 40, Miscellaneous; Sheet Metal Workers' International Association Local 40, The Capitol Ventilating Company; Shelton Police; Thruway Transfer, Incorporated; Van Dyke Printing v. Cooper Jarrett; Wallingford Police; Waterbury Police; West Haven Police (and Weber).
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, financial records, fliers, legal documents, notes, photographs (reproductions of), publications, transcripts, 1965, 1967-1976; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_18)
    Subjects include: Case files #1974.13-#1975.4: A.J.'s Beef Barn, Incorporated; Bridgeport T.U.P.; Campaign Law Test Case; Carpenters Local 79, New Haven; Carpenters Local 1520, Custom Hall Incorporated; Emhart Corporation v. The I.A.M.; Greenwich Carpenters, Arbitration; Hartford Bricklayers; I.B.T. Local 443, Super Market Distributors Incorporated; I.B.T. Local 536, Coca Cola Bottling Company; I.B.T. Local 559; Kelly & Huber, Bricklayers; National Automatic Sprinkler & Fire Control Association; Shindell Trusts; Teamsters Local 443, General; U.S. v. Roberto; Yale University, Federation of Employees, Local 35.
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, notes, publications, transcripts, 1950s, 1961-1975; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_19)
    Subjects include: Case files #1975.5-#1975.12C: Frito-Lay Incorporated, I.B.T. Local 145; I.B.T. Local 671, Wells Fargo; Local 217, Hotel & Restaurant Employees Union; The Ship's Wheel Incorporated v. Anne Birks; The Stamford Transit Company; Vickers Incorporated v. Lovetri; Vickers Incorporated, Sperry Rand Corporation; Victory Plumbing v. Richard Fucci.
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, notes, publications, sketches, transcripts, 1950s, 1960s, 1970-1975; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_20)
    Subjects include: Case files #1975.12D-#1975.24: All State Investment Corporation v. Rafield; Calabro; Carpenters Local 3045, Arbor Homes Incorporated; Chestnut Hill Bus Corporation; Combustion Engineering Incorporated; DALU 24369, Timex Corporation; Donald Crocker; I.B.T. Local 145; Josephine Criscuolo v. Henry Criscuolo; Pilot Freight; Vickers Incorporated; Walsh v. Silliman.
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, map, notes, publications, 1964, 1968-1976; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_21)
    Subjects include: Case files #1975.25-#1975.37: Confinante v. David Monde; Elevator Operations; I.A.M., Carmichael; I.A.M. Partner; I.E.U. 260; Lucy Jerome; New Haven Printing Specialties and Paper Products Union 508; Stamford Firefighters; Teamsters; Training School; Wallingford Firefighters.
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, fliers, legal documents, notes, publications, transcripts, 1956-1959, 1964-1966, 1969-1977; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_22)
    Subjects include: Case files #1975.38-#1975.52: A.I.W., Cuno; A.I.W. Local 641, Richard Grover; Cardell Carpets Incorporated v. The Boulevard Corporation; Connecticut Women's Political Caucus; Gulf Oil; Hotel and Restaurant Employees' and Bartenders' Union Local 217; I.A.M. and U.A.C. cases; I.B.T. Local 536, Seiler Corporation; I.B.T. Local 559, Dobbs Houses Incorporated; International Union of Operating Engineers; Jenkins Brothers, Steelworkers; Masters Report; Nelson Freightways Incorporated; Pexto; Picadilly Square.
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, financial records, fliers, legal documents, maps, notes, publications, transcripts, 1957, 1960-1963, 1965-1968, 1971-1977; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_23)
    Subjects include: Case files #1975.53-#1975.65: AFL-CIO; American Bar Association, OSHA; Eastern Color Printing Company; Fairfield Police; Federation of University Employees Local 35, Yale University; Hummel Corporation, I.U.E. Local 256; I.B.T. Local 443, Addition; I.B.T. Local 559, East Hartford Warehouse Incorporated; I.B.T. Local 671, Benton's Hartford Express Incorporated; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Hartford Electric Light Company; Marvin Cohen; William Andrew.
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, financial records, fliers, legal documents, notes, photographs, posters, publications, 1947-1950, 1954-1957, 1959, 1962-1968, 1971-1979; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_24)
    Subjects include: Case files #1975.67-#1977.69: AMF-CUNO Division; The Austin Company v. International Union of Operating Engineers Local 478; Bridgeport Brass Company, DALU Local 24411; Bridgeport Machines Profit Sharing Plan; Connecticut State Board of Labor Relations v. Connecticut Yankee Greyhound and Connecticut Yankee Catering; Cott Beverage Incorporated, Teamsters Local 443; Custom Hall, CJA Local 1717; David C. Adams v. City of Milford; Garment Workers; Hull's Brewery; I.B.T. Local 443, St. Raphael Hospital; International Union of Operating Engineers Local 478, Civitillo; Joseph Laucella; M. Swift & Sons Incorporated v. I.B.T. Local 1035; Meatcutters 371; Milford Jai Alai; Painters Union Local 186, Pension Fund; Plumbers Local 305; Plumbers Local 676, Manny Russo; Santamassimo; Sheet Metal Workers' International Association Local 40; Stamford Firefighters v. Charles Skiba; Teamsters Local 443, Register Publishing Company; United Furniture Workers of America; United Postal Service, Teamsters Local 671; Universal Travel & Tours Incorporated; William Shames.
  - Administratice records, clippings, correspondence, financial records, fliers, legal documents, notes, publications, transcripts, 1970-1979; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_25)
    Subjects include: Case files #1977.70-#1978.04: A.F.L.; Hilary Gordon v. National Benefit Fund for Hospital and Health Care Employees; Hospital of St. Raphael, Stephenson; I.B.T. Local 493 v. Branford Construction Company; I.B.T. Local 671, National Association of Government Employees; I.B.T. Local 677, International Union of Operating Engineers Local 478 v. Perazzini Construction Company; International Association of Machinists, District 26; Legislation; Manson H. Whitlock v. Vincent J. Sirabella; Operating Engineers, Palmieri; Parts Warehouse Incorporated v. I.B.T. Local 1040; Retail Union Local 282; Sheet Metal Workers Joint Apprenticeship; Sheet Metal Workers Local 40, N.L.R.B.; Sheet Metal Workers Local 346, Albert Scharf; Teamsters Local 671, Connecticut Natural Gas Corporation; Teamsters Local 1035, Hull Brewing Company; United Parcel Service, I.B.T. Local 191; Vincent Pisano; Workman's Compensation Study Commission.
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, notes, posters, publications, 1965-1967, 1970-1979; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_26)
    Subjects include: Case files #1978.34-#1978.56: A.M.F. Cuno Division v. A.I.W. Local 753, Baston; American Airlines; Costello Construction v. Teamsters Local 559; Delaney v. I.B.T. Local 191; George Usher v. I.B.T. Local 191; Gloria Strang v. Mattie Smith; I.B.T. Local 145 v. Connecticut Limousine Service Incorporated; I.B.T. Local 145, Wells Fargo Armored Service Corporation; I.B.T. Local 493 v. R.B. Greene Transportation Incorporated; Operating Engineers Local 478, Castle & Cook; Shindell v. Coppola; Spartaco Petrini et al v. Michael Misenti et al; Taylor & Taylor Trucking Company v. Teamsters Local 493, International Paper Company, Plainfield Service Company; Teamsters Local 191 v. Ryder Truck Rental; Teamsters Local 251 v. Akers Motor Lines Incorporated; Teamsters Local 443, Cott Corporation; Teamsters Local 443, Lefferman.
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, financial records, fliers, legal documents, magnetic disk (tape cassette), notes, posters, publications, transcripts, 1961, 1964-1978; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_27)
    Subjects include: Case files #1978.57-#1978.77: City of Stamford, I.A.F.F. Local 786; Connecticut Foundry Company v. I.L.G.W.U.; Connecticut Light and Power Company v. I.B.E.W. Local 420, Carmine Prestipano; Connecticut Light and Power Company v. I.B.E.W. Local 457, Scovatto; I.B.T. Local 191, Pacelli Brothers Transport Company; I.B.T. Local 493, Strike Arrests; I.B.T. Local 559 v. Union Carbide; I.B.T. Local 677 v. Forest City Express; I.B.T. Local 1040, Standard Auto Equipment Company et al; Painters Local 186, Pension Fund; Teamsters Local 191, general; Teamsters Local 443, Michael Schiavone & Sons Incorporated; Teamsters Local 443, Starr Delivery Service Incorporated, Della Camera; Teamsters Local 493, Mersick & Company; Teamsters Local 677 v. Housatonic Disposal Services; Town of Wallingford v. I.B.E.W. Local 457; Waterbury Printing & Graphic Communications Union Local 150, Eastern Color Printing Company; Whitmire v. C.H.C.P.
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, financial records, fliers, legal documents, notes, posters, publications, sketch (map), transcripts, 1961, 1963-1968, 1970-1979; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_28)
    Subjects include: Case files #1978.78-#1979.02: A.F.L.; Connecticut Foundry Company v. I.L.G.W.U.; Dichello Distributors Incorporated v. Brewery & Soft Drink Workers Local 1040; Fitzgerald Gasket Incorporated v. F.E.F.L.U. #24722; George Ellis Company v. Plumbers and Steamfitters Local 349; I.B.T. Local 191, Ralph Brundage; I.B.T. Local 443 v. Charles Lanzetti; I.B.T. Local 493; I.B.T. Local 493, Cherenzia & Nigrelli; I.B.T. Local 559, David Transportation; I.B.T. Local 671, Hemingway Transport Incorporated; I.B.T. Local 1040, Reliable Wine & Liquor Company; John Cassidento; Margaret Dargon v. Union Labor Life Insurance Company; Plumbers Local 305, Becker & Goldstein Incorporated; Shindell, Bishop Street; Shindell, Howe Street; Subcontracting, 671; Thomas Fiander; Universal Travel.
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, maps, notes, posters, publications, 1974-1979; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_29)
    Subjects include: Case files #1979.03-#1979.27: AMF Cuno Division, A.I.W. Local 753; Carlos Carrasco, Connecticut Foundry Company; County School Service Incorporated; Emanuel Russo; Estate of Sam Samowitz v. Frank Trykoski; First National Stores Incorporated, I.B.T. Local 559; I.B.E.W. Local 90, Ralph Castellon; I.B.E.W. Locals 457 & 420, Connecticut Light & Power Company; I.B.T. Local 671, United Parcel Service; I.B.T. Local 1040 v. Parts Warehouse Incorporated; International Union of Elevator Constructors Local 91 v. General Elevator Company; Joseph Borges; Kraft Dairy Group Incorporated, I.B.T. Local 536; Lehigh Oil Company, I.B.T. Local 493; New Britain Transportation Company, I.B.T. Local 559; Operating Engineers Local 478, Vincent Egidio; Raymond Heroux et al v. I.B.T. Local 677; Red Wing Oil Company, I.B.T. Local 559; Robert L. Harris, First National Stores Incorporated; Town of Wallingford, I.B.E.W. Local 457; Union Carbide Corporation, I.B.T. Local 559; United Illuminating Company, Local 470-471 of the Utility Workers of America.
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, maps, notes, photographs, publications, sketches (preliminary), 1974-1980; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1991.0003_30)